Satyanarayan Dalei

Specializes in web(MERN Stack) development

+91-8144573354

satyaprofessional99@gmail.com

Bhubaneswar, Odisha, India

/Satyana17786386

/in/satyadalei

https://satyadalei.github.io/portfolio/

/satyadalei



Summary

Hi, I am a full-stack developer with 1+ years of experience. I am doing my Master's in Computer Application. I have completed my web development bootcamp from Udemy. Though I have worked on both frontend and backend technology, backend has been my core field of interest so far. I use MongoDB, Express.js, React.js, Node.js, and Bootstrap for building full-stack projects. I am also familiared with the git version control system.

Skills

HTML

CSS

JavaScript

Bootstrap V.5

Node.js

Express.js

React.is

MongoDB

C++ with OOP

Firebase

Git

GitHub

Linux CMD

RESTful API

Education

• 2022 -**Master in Computer Application**

2024 Biju Patnaik University Of Technology, Rourkela Continuing

> Relevant Coursework: Joining Hackathons, Collaborating with classmates to build web application

Batchelor of Science, Major Physics 2018 -North Orissa University, Mayurbhani, Odisha 2021

CGPA: 7.9

Relevant Coursework: Teaching junior students physics, Helping them in lab experiments

Integrated Science • 2016 -

2018 Wisdom Higher secondary Science School, Balasore

CGPA: 75

Matriculation 2013 -

Siba Prasad High School, Saud, Balasore 2016

CGPA: 8.3

Certificates

2020 - Full-stack web development bootcamp

2022 Udemy, Instructor: Angela Yu

> Relevant Coursework: Build Financial management website, BMI calculator, Ludo website Game, did internship @Ms internship & tasked to maintain website

Experience

2021 - 04 Web Developer & Designer 2022 - 04

Ms InfoSystems, Baripada, odisha

- Tasked to update & maintain companies career website regularly.
- Collaboratively working with another copartner for building client's website
- Teaching students HTML, CSS, Javascript both in offline and online(YouTube) as well.

Key achievements

Taught 100+ students satisfactorily in the local language about web development, and built 5+ websites successfully.

2020 - 08 **Photo Editor & Designer** 2021 - 02

Sai Digital studio, Baripada, Odisha

- I was assigned to do old photo restoration, to remove different types of scratches from old photos.
- Designing various posters for social media posts, making visiting cards for business professionals, teachers,

Key achievements

 Learned a lot of things related to design principles such as color combinations, and how to design specifically for the targeted populations.

Key Projects

Money Expense Tracker

Financial management web application || 2022 Aug

- Helps users to track their day to day financial expenditures.
- Tech Stacks: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, EJS

Key achievements

 Helped 50+ active users track expenses after few days of deployment of website.

Happy You : Social Media web app

Daily emotion or mode management || 2023 June

- Helps people track their daily modes, & improve their modes by customized posts. User can share posts & make friends their to get their latest feeds
- Tech Stacks: React.js, Express.js, MongoDB, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, Node.js,

Key achievements

- Got opportunity to interact with senior developers.
- Learned how to work effectively in a collaborative environment, & learn from each other.
- Our project got selected under 30 best hackathon projects & got some digital badges.

TextUtils web application

Text editing web application || 2023 April

- Helps perform simple operations on text, like capitalizing, converting to lowercase, removing unnecessary spaces, counts no. of words used.
- Tech Stacks: React.js, Bootstrap

Key achievements

 It was helpful to many students while customizing their assignments including my classmates.

- It was a hackathon project.
- I collaborated with other teammates of UI/UX designer.
- Completed within 15 days & submitted successfully.
- We are able work remotely smoothly through google meet & slack while building projects.

Languages

- English (Professional Intermediate level)
- Hindi (Moderate level)
- Odia (Native)

Learning Now || 2023 July-Aug

- Java
- DevOps